Guide to the Stanford University, Humanities Honors Program, Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Theses, pre-1990
  - Hoover, Elizabeth C., Self-knowledge., Spring 1973 (Box 8)
  - Hopkins, rdon, The novelist Italo Svevo., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Horgan, Terry, Religious symbols and cognitive statements: a critical discussion of Paul Tillich's Theory of Theological Language., 1970 (Box 8)
  - Horn, Mary, Lu Hsun: The man and his message., 1955 (Box 8)
  - Hornung, Kimberly, Elie Wiesel's concept of the Messiah: a comparison with Sabatianism and Hasidism., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Houston, Holly, The "Medea" according to Euripides: a feminist interpretation of the legal context and the mythical origins of Euripedes' "Medea"., 1975 (Box 8)
  - Howe, Donna, Paul Klee and the dynamics of practical reality., 1969 (Box 8)
  - Huang, Virginia S., Talking intelligently about music: Leonard Meyer's theory on emotion and meaning in music., 1981 (Box 8)
  - Hughes, Harold J., "Kingdom of Dream, Province of Illusion": The Utopias of Calm Felicity., 1969 (Box 8)
  - Humphreys, Anne, The westward movement in eight contemporary American novels., 1959 (Box 8)
  - Huneke, Joan Winnek, An approach through character to a study of Joyce's method., 1961 (Box 8)
  - Hunsinger, George, Kierkegaard, Heidegger, and the concept of death., 1969 (Box 8)
  - Hunter, Robert D., The Deaf Hand: the Chinese intellectual reaction to the West., 1969 (Box 8)
  - Huntsman, Jean, The symbolism of wine in the Dionysian cults, early Judaism and early Christianity., 1977-78 (Box 8)
  - Hymans, Jack L., The impact of bureaucracy on society., 1958-59 (Box 8)
  - Hymens, Herbert Henri Eduard, Pierre Mendes-France, A Solution for France., 1957 (Box 8)
  - Ichien, Arlene, Black consciousness, black persona in America., 1969 (Box 8)
  - Imhoff, Ronald, The development of time consciousness in the major novels of Virginia Woolf. (Box 9)
  - Jackson, Cynthia, The issue of literary freedom in Socialist Cuba., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Jacobs, Caryn, Three salonnieres: traditional means to untraditional ends: a study on the salon worked for the benefit of the salonniere., 1980 (Box 9)
  - James, Dorothy Susan, Christ and Dionysos., 1962 (Box 9)
  - Janeway, Katherine Anne, the impact of millennial expectation on American political and social theory from 1730-1845., 1977 (Box 9)
  - Janssen, Robert S., In search of the Holy Ghost: the influence of Thomas Hardy on the novels of D. H. Lawrence., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Bruce E., God's covenant--man's context., 1963 (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Conrad D., Speculation and Investigation: A comparative study of Schopenhauer and Freud. (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Elizabeth Ann, A critical study of Albert Camus' "Ethic of Rebellion'., 1964 (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Henry C. L., Jr., Satire and the Revolt against reason in three of Doestoevsky's works: Another Man's Wife and the Husband Under the Bed, An Unpleasant Predicament, and Notes from Underground., 1970 (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Kathryn, Some long run cultural implications of the Communist revolution in China., 1965 (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Mark Steven, Mercenary soldiers in Renaissance Florence., Spring 1973 (Box 9)
  - Johnston, Robert K., The spiritual world of T. S. Eliot., 1967 (Box 9)
  - Jones, Kendall M., A comparative view of the problem of evil., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Jordan, Marilyn, Revivalism and the Romantic in America, 1789-1830., 1958 (Box 9)
  - Joynes, D. Carroll, The riddle of faith: a comparative study of Cardinal Newman and Lev Shestov., Spring 1973 (Box 9)
  - Kadden, Bruce, Liberation theology: a comparative analysis., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kahn, Jonathan, the political economy of Thorstein Veblen and John Kenneth Galbraith., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Kalin, Jesse Gene, The ethical implications of Alfred North Whitehead's metaphysics., 1962 (Box 9)
  - Kanner, Jaclyn A., The inanimate and the inability to love in Thomas Pynchon's V.., May 1, 1982 (Box 22)
  - Kantor, Betty, The sin of pride in Chaucer's "Pardoner's Tale"., 1960 (Box 9)
  - Kaplan, Howard J., Humanism in George Orwell's Nineteen Eighty-Four., May 1985 (Box 22)
  - Karl, Terry, The Development of an aesthetic philosopy in The Notebooks of Malte Laurids Brigge., 1970 (Box 9)
  - Katz, Michael Steven, Federico Fellini: An Artist's Discoveries in Reality. (Box 9)
  - Kaye, Howard J., Satiric Method in Aldous Huxley and Evelyn Waugh., 1964 (Box 9)
  - Keeney, Willard, Hawthorne and the artist., 1963 (Box 9)
  - Kehl, Kathleen, National Socialism and the German character in the works of Thomas Mann., 1964 (Box 9)
  - Keily, Jane Marie Yett, Teilhard de Chardin's Image of Man., 1969 (Box 9)
  - Kent, Susan, Comic form and narration in three novels by William Faulkner., 1967 (Box 9)
  - Kernaghan, Ronald J., The Role of the hero in the work of Soren Kierkegaard., 1969 (Box 9)
  - Kerston, Teresa E., Men for all seasons: the faithful in Joseph Conrad., November 13, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Kier, Deborah L., Courtly love in the Renaissance epic: Ariosto, Tasso, Spenser, and Milton., 1975 (Box 10)
  - Kim, Gloria S., The abortion issue: historical and modern perspectives., 1979 (Box 10)
  - Kimball, Ann, The architecture of light in Dante's Paradiso., 1972 (Box 10)
  - Kimball, Jeffrey, Bridging the visual void: a survey of the motion picture medium in the age of expanding technology., 1980 (Box 10)
  - Kircher, Charles W., Democracy and Esther in the education of Henry Adams. (Box 10)
  - Kirkish, Noel Arlen, Five elements of painting., 1961 (Box 10)
  - Kirkpatrick, Lou Anne, The American myth., 1958 (Box 10)
  - Kirschner, Robert S., The technique of fiction in Unamuno's Niebla., April 1972 (Box 10)
  - Kitts, Leonore, Il combattimento di Tancredi e clorinda: The rhythm of emotion., June 10, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Klatzkin, Amy, Peter Handke: the first five plays., 1978 (Box 10)
  - Klein, James B., Toward an Understanding of Fascism., 1964 (Box 10)
  - Klein, Patrick F., Cold War Liberalism: American liberal social thought in the 1950s., 1970 (Box 10)
  - Kleinman, Arthur M., The American Depression and the Depression Authors., 1962 (Box 10)
  - Klopka, Susanne H., The Quest for Human Happiness: A comparative examination of the Faustian dilemma in Goethe and Valery., Spring 1983 (Box 22)
  - Kneedler, Susan J., The vision of relationships in the fiction and essays of D. H. Lawrence., 1978 (Box 10)
  - Knipprath, Debbie Duncan, Joaquin Miller, California personified., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Knowlton, Jeffrey W., Surffering and responses to suffering in Job, Ecclesiastes, and Waiting for Godot., Spring 1984 (Box 22)
  - Knudson, Pam, Ritual: a definitional process., 1970 (Box 10)
  - Koch, David Allan, The existential quest in the novels of Hermann Hesse. (Box 10)
  - Koehler, Kyle, Dazai Osamu: the cycle of tension between life and art., May 1984 (Box 22)
  - Kohn, Lynette, Graham Greene: the major novels., 1961 (Box 10)
  - Koshkarian, Gregory M., Thomas Mann: from culture to politics., 1984 (Box 22)
  - Kraft, John Kersten, The flesh as flame., 1966 (Box 10)
  - Kreigshauser, Catherine A., The opposition of intellect and feeling, and the solution of the dichotomy in Robert Musil's The man without qualities., 1975 (Box 10)
  - Kremen, Alan, Education in the philosopy of Heraclitus and Parmenides. (Box 10)
  - Kremers, Carolyn Sue, Flesh into flowers: perceptivism in Claude Debussy and Virginia Woolf., Spring 1973 (Box 10)
  - Kreps, Marta Lise, The translation of the classical ideal in Goethe: a comparative study., September 25, 1981 (Box 22)
  - Kroeger, Linda, The philosophic and dramatic concept of tragedy in Buero Vallejo's theater., 1960 (Box 10)
  - Kuckenberg, Joan, Mysticism and the modern man., 1957 (Box 10)
  - Kulhanjian, Julie Ann, The plague in Western literature., 1981 (Box 10)
  - Kwong, Karen, Women, Conformity and question: the search for individual freedom in Eastern and Western culture through the works of: Kate Chopin: The Awakening, Edith Wharton: The House of Mirth, Pa Chin: Family, Maxine Hong Kinston: The Woman Warrir., May 1985 (Box 22)
  - Ladra, Michael R., Aspects of Jean-Paul Sartre's Development. (Box 11)
  - Lande, Janet Marie, Kierkegaard's concept of ethics in Either/Or and Fear and Trembling and its relationship with Hegel., June 1972 (Box 11)
  - Lane, Margaret J., Prophets of industry and democracy: The social theories of Saint Simon and Tocqueville., June 1982 (Box 22)
  - Laney, David, The secret of the murmuring: an interpretation of Whitman. (Box 11)
  - Langenthal, Sara, The non-Euclidean revolution: its origins and implications. (Box 11)
  - Larmer, Billie, The Organ of Attention to Life. (Box 11)
  - Larson, Carol S., Hitlerjugend: a description and a normative evaluation., 1975 (Box 11)
  - Lasarow, Richard M., The myth of self: a study in romantic mythmaking and its application in the present., 1974 (Box 11)
  - Law, Judith H., Existential thought on History., 1962-63 (Box 11)
  - Lawrence, David, The spiritual jounrey of the young Lukacs., June 1984 (Box 22)
  - Lawrence, John, Hamlet and psychoanalytical literary criticism., 1960 (Box 11)
  - Leiderman, Erica, The dialectic of Bildung: a study of four novels., 1978 (Box 11)
  - Leipzig, Matt, Boccaccio's Allegory and the reader's role: Decameron 2.5., Spring 1982 (Box 22)
  - Leitzell, Katharyn, The problem of neo-conformity in contemporary America., 1958 (Box 11)
  - Lercara, Lynn, Dance philosophy with emphasis on Isadora Duncan., 1956 (Box 11)
  - Levin, Larry, Michael Polanyi: The role of the individual in science., 1969 (Box 11)
  - Levine, Audrey E., Adrienne Rich: A Re-vision of power., 1984 (Box 22)
  - Levinson, Henry Samuel, Cassirer, Eliade, and Polanyi on the nature of man's consciousness., 1970 (Box 11)
  - Lewis, Alan C. R., Nature and culture in theepical, polemical, and crisis-oriented works of Leo Tolstoy., Spring 1973 (Box 12)
  - Lewis, Madeline A., Students of an institution: the portrayal of the undergraduate experience in American university fiction., 1974 (Box 12)
  - Lincoln, Kenneth R., A sense of timeless being., 1965 (Box 12)
  - Liner, Robert I., Inside a song: the dream of fantasy in J. R. R. Rolkin's The Lord of the Rings., 1966 (Box 12)
  - Linvill, Candace Sue, "The compelling inward ring": a discussion of fantasy's special appeal as seen in eight works of fantasy literature., 1974 (Box 12)
  - Lloyd, Charles, Arthur Koestler: a Study in Responsibility., 1957 (Box 12)
  - Lloyd, Michael A., John Dewey's analysis of education and democracy: the problems of achieving individual fulfillment., 1975 (Box 12)
  - Long, David S., Michael Polanyi and fiduciary philosophy., 1960 (Box 12)
  - Longinotti, Richard F., Dietrich Bonhoeffer's criticism of religion and its application to the theology of St. Thomas Aquinas., 1974 (Box 12)
  - Look, Kelly Anne, Ethics and medicine: the moral dilemma of euthenasia., Spring 1985 (Box 22)
  - Love, Brett J., Nietzsche: the use of myth and the death of tragedy as culture criticism., 1983 (Box 22)
  - Lowe, Mary P., The concept of identity in works of Hesse and Frisch. (Box 12)
  - Lurie, Barry, The end of the enigma: the Brothers Karamozov as a cathartic rejection of Dostoevsky's radicalism., June 2, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Macie, Christopher John, Music as a Moment in the Western tradition; Aesthetic and foundational moments in the dialectic of music experience., 1964 (Box 12)
  - MacLean, Douglas E., Analysis and Christian Ethics. (Box 12)
  - Maloney, Mary Grace, Central Valley mythology: the works of Gerald W. Haslam., Spring 1985 (Box 22)
  - Manes, Dorothy, A study of scholastic and Hindi aesthetics., 1952 (Box 13)
  - Mark, Sara, Charles Baudelaire and Edouard Manet: modern artistic visions., 1975-76 (Box 13)
  - Marz, Charles, The quest for pure representation: a critical study of the works of D. H. Lawrence and Samuel Beckett., 1971 (Box 13)
  - Massey, Walter F., The white man's burden., 1966 (Box 13)
  - Mathews, Amoretta, Freedom in four "Utopian" societies., 1962-63 (Box 13)
  - Matsukewa, Lori, Literary impressionism in The Ambassadors and "The Aspern Papers"., 1978 (Box 13)
  - Mattson, Robert, Jr., Kafka's The Castle and Sartre's Being and Nothingness: prophetic phenomenology., 1971 (Box 13)
  - May, Viviane, Andre Malraux and the tragic hope., 1954 (Box 13)
  - McBride, Lawrence, Ambrose Bierce: Romancer and Iconoclast., 1970 (Box 12)
  - McClung, Susan, Youth, old age, and women in Euripidean drama with a focus on the powerful characters in the Bacchae and the Alcestis., 1977 (Box 12)
  - McClure, Jean, Man and his democracy., 1955 (Box 12)
  - McCord, Anne, Graham Greene's obsession with evil in the five major novels., 1963 (Box 12)
  - McCrary, Jerel, D. H. Lawrence and Bernard Shaw: prophets of new creeds., 1974 (Box 12)
  - McCulloch, Carolyn, Contemporary French Interpretations of Classical Tragedy., 1958 (Box 12)
  - McDonald, Mary, The existence of humanity., 1969 (Box 12)
  - McDonell, Stephanie, Art and existence in the remembrance of things past--Proust., 1963 (Box 12)
  - McEvoy, E. P., Political aspects of Shaw's criticism., 1959 (Box 12)
  - McFadden, Elizabeth, The ethic of freedom: a study in the existentialism of Jean-Paul Sartre., 1957 (Box 12)
  - McGaughey, Margaret D., Love and Marriage in Anna Karenina., 1970 (Box 12)
  - McGregor, Robert, The ethic of Albert Camus: A critical essay., 1965 (Box 12)
  - McIlvaine, William B., An actual earth of value., 1974 (Box 12)
  - McIntyre, Jerilyn, Humor in the works of Mark Twain., 1964 (Box 12)
  - McKanna, Carol, A television dramatist as an artist: Reginald Rose., 1960 (Box 13)
  - McLean, Cheryl, Henrik Ibsen and James Joyce: The self-consciousness of the Artist., 1980 (Box 13)
  - McLellan, Beth, The transformation of style in the work of Francisco Goya., May 1972 (Box 13)
  - McMillan, Gina, The Book of Job: The influence of the Archetype on modern literature., 1980 (Box 13)
  - McNagny, Sally E., The implications of the hermetic and picaresque elements in Confessions of Felix Krull Confidence Man (The Early Years)., 1980 (Box 13)
  - Means, Peggy Ann, The intellectual's role in society: a study of the criticism of Edmund Wilson., 1978 (Box 13)
  - Medved, Marianne, The possibility of the doctrine of fall as insight into the human condition: Paul Tillich and Thomas Aquinas., 1969 (Box 13)
  - Meek, Marjorie, The horrible family ghost: the religious views of William and Henry James., 1975 (Box 13)
  - Melgarejo, Monica S., Gabriel Garcia Marquez and disintegration and solitude in some of his work., Summer 1981 (Box 22)
  - Melody, Moya, King Arthur as a hero in the works of Sir Thomas Malory., 1969 (Box 13)
  - Meredith, David, The search for meaning: moral value in the philosophy of William James., 1964 (Box 13)
  - Merrill, Charles E., Reason and faith in the works of John Donne, Sir Thomas Browne, and Sir Francis Bacon., 1974 (Box 13)
  - Messer, John W., The blues and Bessie Smith., 1972? (Box 13)
  - Messinger, Gary, John Milton's road to Republicanism., 1965 (Box 13)
  - Metzenbaum, Shelley H., The representation of reality in the Travels of Lao Ts'An., 1974 (Box 13)
  - Meyers, Sharon E., The language of Synge., Spring 1973 (Box 13)
  - Middlekauff, Alice, Pre-arranged marriage: an analysis of a dominant Lorquian theme., 1955 (Box 14)
  - Miles, Graham M., Reflections toward an Unknown God., 1969 (Box 14)
  - Miller, Angela, "Sea change" and conversion: stages of the American imagination in Henry James., 1976 (Box 14)
  - Miller, B. Jaye, The Christian Renaissance of Utopian writing., 1964 (Box 14)
  - Miller, Barbara S., The emergence of the individual., 1976 (Box 14)
  - Miller, David Cameron, The transfiguration of language and the American sublime., 1974 (Box 14)
  - Miller, John E., The "Gospel of Wealth" in the 1950s., 1961 (Box 14)
  - Miller, R. Scott, The artistic Socrates and Zarathustra., 1977 (Box 14)
  - Miller, Stuart, Soviet Russia and the United States., 1949 (Box 14)
  - Miller, Tim, The Jonsonian trickster in Milton's Satan., 1981 (Box 14)
  - Mills, Joel Robert, Jr., The individual and society in the drama of Bertolt Brecht. (Box 14)
  - Mitchell, Donald, Bach's St. Matthew passion: a psychology of inspirational art. (Box 14)
  - Mitchell, Jo Ellen, Hofmannsthal's criticism: a quest to fulfill the poetic mission., 1972 (Box 14)
  - Moe, Stephen A., The nation triumphant: the historical writings of Henry Adams, Theodore Roosevelt, and Woodrow Wilson., 1971 (Box 14)
  - Monach, Andrew E., Fragments from a family., 1976 (Box 14)
  - Moore, Ronald, Metaphysical symbolism in T. S. Eliot's "Four Quartets"., 1966 (Box 14)
  - Moran, Mark Sean, Rendering Extremity: A textual comparison of Camus and Levi., June 10, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Mortimer, Ann, Nathaniel Hawthorne's and Francois Mauriac's tapestries of life and religion., 1976 (Box 14)
  - Moseley, Carol, A modern pilgrimage to Canterbury: Three playwrights in search of Thomas Beckett., 1966 (Box 14)
  - Moseley, Susan D., Expression in many literary forms: a study of C. S. Lewis., 1974 (Box 14)
  - Mossman, Lois, In the course of a lifetime: an historical view of Thomas Mann., 1955 (Box 14)
  - Muir, Janet, The never-ending meditation., 1971 (Box 14)
  - Mullins, Greg A., A view into the Sun: Heiner Muller's Revolutionary Theater., April 1985 (Box 22)
  - Munholland, Kim, Ideas and attitudes in Ernest Hemingway., 1956 (Box 14)
  - Murphy, Margueritte S., Mood, dancer, and swan: echoes of Mallarmean symbolism in Yeats' thought and works., 1977 (Box 14)
  - Murray, Craig C., United States policy and Communist China., 1960 (Box 14)
  - Murray, Kevin M., Causality and determinism: connections and complications., 1974 (Box 14)
  - Mushkin, Steve, The civilized and the savage: Man's return to nature in King Lear, Timon of Athens, and The Tempest., 1979 (Box 14)
  - Nadelhaft, Paula, "Let Cromwels nose still riegn": perspectives of the Lord Protector., 1978 (Box 15)
  - Nakadate, Neil, The tin drum: a twentieth century comic-grotesque study., 1965 (Box 15)
  - Neils, Eric W., St. Ignatius and Shakespeare: meditation and manipulation., 1978 (Box 15)
  - Noonan, Timothy T., Themes of escape in American literature., 1975 (Box 15)
  - O'Hara, David, The doctriine of man in the theology of Reinhold Niebuhr., 1956 (Box 15)
  - O'Keefe, Maureen T., Alive in art: Emma Bovary, Isabel Archer, Gerty MacDowell., 1974 (Box 15)
  - O'Neill, Kathleen M., The experience of Twelfth Night., 1975 (Box 15)
  - O'Shea, Lester, The decline of colonialism., 1959 (Box 15)
  - Oakford, Fred, The Victorians of Bloomsbury., 1971 (Box 15)
  - Oates, Mollie, "Hast any philosophy in thee, shepherd?" A Study of the Function of Nature and Art in Shakespeare's Tragi-comedies., 1959 (Box 15)
  - Odell, Harriett, The suffering individual in Unamuno., 1958 (Box 15)
  - Olson, Yvonne, Ethics in Nietzsche and Fromm., 1960 (Box 15)
  - Oshetsky, Claire, Die Rose Schonheit Soll Nicht Sterbern: Paul Celan's translations of Shakespeare's sonnets., 1984 (Box 15)
  - Oxtoby, Louise Gurdon, An old art in a new age: contemporary stained glass., 1960 (Box 15)
  - Oxtoby, Willard G., The Christian philosophy of Origen., 1955 (Box 15)
  - Ozawa, Carol Lynn Sachiye, Issei, Nisei, Sansei: A blend of East and West., April 1983 (Box 22)
  - Packer, Barbara, The Motley Crew: audience as fool in Tristram Shandy., 1969 (Box 15)
  - Parish, John L., Is God Dead in black America? the faces and phases of black religion., 1970 (Box 15)
  - Parks, Patricia, The Enlightment's new look at suicide., 1967 (Box 15)
  - Parsons, William T., Parapsychology, materialism, and the mind-body problem., 1977 (Box 15)
  - Patton, Marilyn, Personal history., 1970 (Box 15)
  - Paul, Mimi, Communication incorporated., December 14, 1983 (Box 23)
  - Pearson, Steven D., Science, society, and ethics: T. H. Huxley and the impact of Darwinism., April 19, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Pedreira, Ann, Finding the woman within: H. D.'s transcendence of the World War II years through Tribute to Freud and Trilogy., April 1982 (Box 23)
  - Perl, Jeffrey M., Except in tendency: T. S. Eliot and the dilemma of post-symbolist classicism., 1974 (Box 15)
  - Perlis, Andrea L., I Malavoglia: Toward defining the narrator., 1980 (Box 15)
  - Perloff, Carey Elizabeth, Artful destruction: patterns of language in The WAste Land and The Satyricon., 1980 (Box 15)
  - Peter, Kenneth B., The spirit of common property., 1981 (Box 15)
  - Peterkort, Carol, Honor, society, and the Homeric hero: a comparison of the Iliad and the Odyssey. (Box 15)
  - Peterson, Anya, An acculturational study of some dances of Oaxaca, Mexico. (Box 15)
  - Peterson, Eric D., Threads of an unchanging scientific aesthetic in Heisenberg's reformulation of atomic physics 1920-25., May 1984 (Box 23)
  - Peterson, Karen, Influences upon American history texts., 1958 (Box 15)
  - Petty, Kathleen, A house of learning and a house of prayer: Mormon education 1830-1870., 1971 (Box 15)
  - Phillips, Gary, A realistic ocean regime: capabilities of producing ethical results., 1976 (Box 15)
  - Phillips, Helen, J. M. Keynes' vision and technique., 1950 (Box 15)
  - Pike, Byrne W., Greek Humanism in twentieth century America., 1949 (Box 15)
  - Popalisky, David J., Bob Dylan: love and the blues., 1977 (Box 15)
  - Pope, Norris F. Jr., D. H. Lawrence and his sense of life. (Box 16)
  - Posner, David Matthew, La Vision Jalouse: Jealousy in the works of Moliere., June 1984 (Box 23)
  - Potter, Alison, The golden laughter of Friedrich Nietzsche and Elie Wiesel., 1977 (Box 16)
  - Potter, Daniel L., Finding a city to live in: metaphor and urban subjectivity in Baudelaire and Mayakovsky., June 1984 (Box 23)
  - Pressman, Edward, Humor as humor: the difficulty of a transcendental perspective., 1965 (Box 16)
  - Prier, Raymond A., The problem of Werther: studies of love and the artist., 1961 (Box 16)
  - Pringle, Elizabeth, The Cathedral of Modena and the revival of Roman Law., 1964 (Box 16)
  - Purcell, Arlyn, Frankenstein's creature had no mother: Women, the family, and Industrialism in America., 1983 (Box 23)
  - Pursell, Willene van Loenen, Love and Marriage in three English authors: Chaucer, Milton, and Eliot., 1963 (Box 16)
  - Quattrocki, Elizabeth, Leonardo da Vinci's anatomical studies: The relationship between his science and his art., 1985 (Box 23)
  - Quinn, John R., A search for a modern aesthetic., 1948 (Box 6)
  - Rashid, Richard F., Marlowe's Faustus: a re-evaluation., 1974 (Box 16)
  - Ratner, Karen, The Arthurian legend: unity in two eras., 1967 (Box 16)
  - Read, Tory, From vision to the soul: a comparative study of Picasso, Colette, Brassai, and Cartier-Bresson., 1984 (Box 23)
  - Reeves, Brian A., Erasmus on history., Spring 1982 (Box 23)
  - Reifler, Victoria E., A critique of anthropological method., 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Resnick, Mike, Where Art, thought and society meet: Frank Lloyd Wright in the Prarie years-the importance of the individual in American architecture., Spring 1985 (Box 23)
  - Rhyne, Elisabeth, Georg Buchner's response to his time: the insistence on complexity., 1976 (Box 16)
  - Richard, Susan L., Judaism in the works of Franz Kafka, Elie Wiesel, and Saul Bellow., 1974 (Box 16)
  - Rideout, Jeffrey A., American and the First World War: changing perceptions from 1914 to 1917., 1983 (Box 23)
  - Riechert, Ann Lorraine, Justice and John Galsworthy: idealism and pragmatism., 1977 (Box 16)
  - Rind, Miles Kallen, Wittgenstein's method: a study in "Philosophical Investigations"., 1982 (Box 23)
  - Riper, Alissa, Religious themes in The Chronicles of Narnia., 1984 (Box 23)
  - Ripley, Charles, Multileveled mimesis: a study of mirrors in the novels of Vladimir Nabokov., 1971 (Box 16)
  - Robb, Walter E., The living soul: a psychological examination of Dostoyevsky with reference to the thought of Plato and Aquinas., 1975 (Box 16)
  - Roberts, Thomas M., The Waste Land as pastoral elegy., 1982 (Box 23)